(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E09 -= Carols.Church =- Subripped by zerox
她怒气冲冲地下来了
Here she comes and she's mad!
凯罗，又搬下来了？
Have you finished moving your science project, Carol?
是的
You bet!
对不起，宝贝 我们需要腾出一个房间
We're sorry, sweetheart. But we needed the guest room.
于是把我的火山扔到街上？
So you throw my volcano out on the street?
这就不对了
That's wrong, Mom.
火山留着，凯罗扔出去
I say we keep the volcano, and just throw Carol out onto the street!
凯罗，对不起
Carol, we're all sorry.
杰夫的法学院入学面试提早了
It's just that Jeff's law school interview got moved up a week.
-这种事常有 -行了，我已经尽了力打扫
- These things happen. - Well, I've cleaned it up as best I could.
还有灰尘的话，就去告我吧!
If he finds any soot in his bed, he can sue me!
杰夫怕有23岁了
Boy, Jeff must be 23 by now?
他家搬到俄亥俄州后就没见过
I don't think we've seen him since Fred and Doris moved to Ohio...
-有5，6年了吧？ -是啊
- what, five, six years ago? - Yeah.
不知道杰夫的牙齿问题怎样了
Hope they've resolved that situation with his teeth.
对!我记起来了
Oh, yeah! Now, I remember this guy!
“嗨，我是杰夫”
"Hi! I'm Jeff! "
够了!杰夫是个好孩子 现在过来住
Can it, you guys! Now, Jeff's a nice boy and while he's in our house...
我们要把他当作一家人
I expect you to treat him like one of the family.
最好把他当作人看待
Better yet, treat him like a human being.
-恐怕他来了 -不必起来
- Probably him. - No, please, don't get up!
我很乐意为家人做事
I rather enjoy doing all the work in the house.
凯罗，对别人好一点
Carol, be nice.
爸爸!我什么时候对别人不.
Come on, Dad! When have you ever known me not to be...
-好! -凯罗？
- nice. - Carol?
女大十八变!
Boy, somebody's really grown up!
牙齿也变了
And somebody's really been to an orthodontist.
毕业后我去了南美洲旅行
Well, after I graduated, I decided to do some traveling in South America.
-谈谈见闻吧! -参加里约的狂欢节.
- Give us the highlights! - Well, I went to Carnival in Rio...
接着在安第斯攀岩 后来在波哥大得了痢疾
then I did some rock-climbing in the Andes, and then I got dysentery in Bogota!
真是令人神往!
That sounds fascinating!
你显然没得过痢疾
You've obviously never had dysentery.
说说巴西好吗？我一直很想去
So, tell us about Brazil, Jeff? I've always wanted to go there.
太棒了，她的人民，历史，文化
It was spectacular. The people, the history, the culture.
我听说有许多天体海滩
I hear they got a lot of nude beaches there.
麦克!他真幼稚
Mike! He's so immature.
麦克，天体海滩没什么意思
Nude beaches aren't so great, Mike.
是啊，不穿衣服钥匙放哪？
Yeah, where are you supposed to keep your keys?
可以挂在.
You can hang them on your--
我只是想说“挂在耳朵上”
I was going to say "ear."
下面咱玩玩游戏
Okay, we're ready for a little Trivial Pursuit.
好!怎么分队？
Great! What are the teams?
我可不要和本一队
Hey, I'm not getting stuck with Ben again.
他回答不出问题就会生气
When he doesn't know the answer, he gets huffy.
我没有!
I do not!
本，我和你一队
Okay, Ben, I'll be on your team.
我又要带爸爸了
Oh, great! Now I have to carry Dad again.
等一下，杰夫是客，理应先挑
Wait a minute, Jeff's our guest. He should get to pick.
-杰夫，你挑 -好，问个问题
- Yeah, Jeff, you pick! - Okay, one question:
的作者是谁？ 硫磺酸的方程式是什么？
Who wrote Gulliver's Tra vels, what's the chemical formula for sulfuric acid...
还有火地岛在哪？
and wheres Tierra del Fuego?
琼纳斯，H2SO4，阿根廷南端!
Jonathan Swift, H2SO4, the southermost tip of Argentina!
我选你!
There's my partner!
-笑什么？ -我在想.
- What's so funny? - I was just thinking about...
昨晚的凯罗暗恋杰夫了
Carol and Jeff last night. She has such a crush on him.
不!
No!
我还记得初一时的怀特女老师
Well, I remember Miss White, my seventh-grade biology teacher.
对，那叫男女关系，而不叫暗恋
Course, that was more of a relationship than a crush.
全班男同学都跟她有“男女关系”
And I bet every boy in your class had the same "relationship."
不是的!我是不同的
No! I was different!
只有我才能情节她的仓鼠笼子
I was the only guy allowed to clean out the hamster cage.
-也不是好差事 -笼子在她家
- Sounds pretty torrid. - it was in her apartment.
地图找到了，我要去看望维拉姑妈
Well, I found that road map. Now, I really have to visit Aunt Vera.
老以为自己身怀绝症的维拉姑妈？
Aunt Vera's the one who's always dreaming up those fatal diseases?
你说得出的绝症他都以为自己感染了
You name it, she's almost died from it!
下面的是超级球员!
And now, for the Huntington Huskies!
场上的68号，大家心中的1号
He's number 68 in your program, and number one in your hearts.
也就是瞌睡虫本.西弗!
It's Ben "The Sandman" Seaver!
瞌睡虫，美国大众都想知道 为什么你叫“瞌睡虫”？
Sandman, all of America wants to know, why do they call you "The Sandman"?
因为被我撞到的人都会不省人事!
Because when I hit them, I put them to sleep!
-本，打什么位置？ -防守拦截
- What position do you play, Ben? - Defensive tackle.
不愧是条壮汉？ 体重多少？280？285？
One of the big boys, huh? What do you tip the scales at, 280? 285?
73.5磅
Seventy-three and a half.
今天他要对付联队最高大的前锋!
Today he goes against the biggest offensive lineman in the league!
“超级珍宝”卢切斯基 137公分，81磅
Yeah, "Jumbo Jimbo" Luzetski. 46", 81 pounds.
听说他能一次吃掉整个汉堡包
They say he can eat a whole cheeseburger in one sitting.
杰夫，最后一次问你
Hey, last chance, Jeff.
要去橄榄球赛吗？
Sure you don't wanna join us for some pee wee football?
不用看比赛.
Yeah and you don't even have to watch the game.
留意女观众就好了
Most guys just watch the Pee-wee-ettes!
我也想去 但是我答应了探望维拉姑妈
I'd really love to, guys, but I promised my Aunt Vera I'd stop by...
好让她连续说半个小时.
so she could do this for half an hour:
“我都快死了，怎么不多来电？”
"Oh, Jeffy, I'll be dead soon. Why don't you call more? "
若是她真的死了，赶回来看比赛吧
Hey, if she's dead when you get there, why don't you swing on by the game?
-麦克! -说笑而已
- Mike! - Just kidding.
-都快走了，凯罗呢？ -妈，我去叫她
- Well, we're about ready. Where's Carol? - You want me to get her for you, Mom?
喂!坏八怪!
Yo! Rhinobreath!
谢谢你，麦克
Thank you, Mike.
你真是.
Mike, you are such a....
杰夫!
Oh, hi, Jeff!
-嗨! -准备好去看比赛没？
- Hi! - Carol, you ready to go to the game?
我要等香蕉饼凉快下来
I've got to watch my banana bread cool.
我不是物理学家 但我认为它冷却并不需要你
Well, Carol, I'm no physicist, but I think it can manage without you.
爸爸，我不能置之不理
I can't abandon it now, Dad.
我是陪着这块香蕉饼长大的!
I've been with this bread since it was dough!
好吧，队伍们，前进!
Well, okay. Let's go, team!
-再见! -再见
- Bye, guys! - So long.
-我要走了 -今天有什么节目？
- Well, I'm out of here. - What do you have planned for today?
这个，探望一个亲戚.
Well, gonna visit a relative...
接着跟朋友在城里吃饭 然后去看戏
then I'm gonna meet a friend in the city for dinner and a show.
看什么戏？
What are you going to see?
-格什温的新闹剧 -我最喜欢格什温了
- The new Gershwin revue. - I just love Gershwin.
他的音乐真的有.
His music is so...
音乐的味道
musical.
喂？不，这里没有人叫“大笨蛋”
Hello? No, there's no "Spudbrain" here.
凯罗，找我的，谢谢
Carol, I think that's for me. Thanks.
汤米老兄!你这混蛋!
Yo, Tommy, buddy, bro! You jerk!
那两张票我怎么办？
What am I supposed to do with these two tickets?
好吧，我也很高兴能跟你通电话 “大笨蛋”，再见
Fine, yeah. Great. Good talking to you, too, Spudbrain. Bye.
-凯罗？ -什么事？
- Carol? - Yeah, Jeff?
今晚有什么节目？
What are you doing tonight?
-吃香蕉饼 -糟了!
- Eating banana bread. - Darn. Shoot. Heck.
-还以为你有空 -我可以抽身出来
- I was hoping you weren't busy. - I can get out of it.
要陪我去看戏吗？
Would you like to see the Gershwin revue tonight?
见鬼，没时间准备
Gee. Shucks. Such short notice!
-去它的香蕉饼! -好，今晚来接你
- What the heck! - Great. Pick you up at your place?
知道我住哪吗？
You know where I live?
浴室旁边第二间房间!
Let's see, second door from the bathroom!
-对 -对了!
- Right. - Gotcha!
★我的爱人.
Someday he'll come along
★某天你总会出现
The man I love
★他秋天要到纽约念法律大学
And he'll be going to NYU Law School in the fall
★我的爱人
The man I love
第二次开球!他遥望敌阵
Hut two! He looks downfield...
发现一名老将无人防守
he's got the wily old veteran in the open!
完美的传球，中庸的接球 等等.
Perfect pass, mediocre catch and wait....
又一名拦截屠夫本.西弗出现!
Yes, another tackle for Ben "The Meat Cleaver" Seaver!
-你们饿了吗？ -不饿，我把“超级珍宝”吃下去了
- Are you guys hungry? - Not me. I had Jumbo Jim for lunch!
好吧，来人上汉堡包
All right. Somebody get this kid a cheeseburger.
-一整个？ -对，肉馅要生的!
- A whole one? - Yeah, and make it raw!
我也不想一副妈妈的模样.
Hey, I hate to sound like a mother here...
但你们是否非得打烂东西才罢休？
but you guys won't be happy until you've broken something, will you?
-不是的 -不
- Nope! - No.
好吧，队员们，洗澡去!
Okay, team, hit the showers!
本，在厅里练习开球!
Okay, Ben. Punting practice is in the living room!
-好! -说笑而已!
- All right! - Joke, Mom, joke!
知道你的女儿今晚有节目吗？
So, have you heard what your daughter has planned for tonight?
她又打算分类国家地理杂志？
Not cross-indexing her National Geographics again.
不，她要和杰夫到城里吃饭，看戏
No. She's going to dinner and the theater in the city with Jeff.
听起来就像约会
That sounds a lot like a date.
这也是凯罗的想法
I'm afraid that's what Carol thinks.
但杰夫只是把她当作小妹妹
And Jeff just thinks he's taking his little friend Carol out to see a show.
说对了
You got it!
我们也不能太保护她.. 不让她去，这样她会心碎
Well, we shouldn't be too protective and tell her she can't go. Shell be crushed.
我们也不能让她去 知道自己误会后.
Yeah, but if we let her go and then she finds out she's taking it all wrong...
她也会心碎
shell be crushed.
至少她能观看一部好戏
Well, at least shell get to see a good show first.
-杰森.. -也许凯罗并没有.
- Jason-- - Well, Maggie, maybe Carol isn't quite...
像我们想象中那样怀春 她在某种程度上会意识到.
as carried away as we think. I'm sure, on some level, she realizes...
杰夫是个大人，她还是个小孩
Jeff's an adult and she's still a child.
瞧瞧
Look at this.
我的妈呀!
Holy cow!
谢谢
Thank you.
戏真好看，座无虚席
Boy, the show was great. The theater was packed.
橄榄球赛的晚上都是如此
It's always like that on Helmet Night.
谢谢
Thank you.
-她真漂亮 -她还好
- She's very pretty. - She's okay.
她算还好“的话，什么算”漂亮？
If she's only "okay, " I'd like to see your idea of "great."
外貌不代表一切，她好像很笨
Looks aren't everything. She looks a little dopey to me.
你喜欢聪明的女人？
So, your ideal woman should be intelligent?
是的，我喜欢聪明的女人.
Yeah, I like an intellectual woman...
她必须懂得浪漫.
but she should be romantic, too...
但不能太得意忘形
but not take herself too seriously.
-就是这样! -还有什么？
- Yeah, like that! - What else?
等等
Wait a minute.
你有心上人吗？
You have somebody specific in mind, don't you?
-有 -莱斯莉!
- Yes. - Leslie!
-莱斯莉？ -杰夫？
- Leslie? - Jeffrey!
-杰夫？ -民工杰夫!是你
- Jeffrey? - Jeffrey, Jeffrey, Jeffrey Backman! It's you.
莱斯莉，真不敢相信 还以为你在伦敦呢？
Leslie, I don't believe this. I thought you we're in London!
是的，但我和演艺老师吵架
Yes, well, I got in a fight with my acting coach.
他坚持让我穿短背心演麦克白 [莎翁名剧]
He insisted I play Lady Macbeth in a tank top.
-这样演我会去看! -你当然了
- Hey, I'd go! - I'm sure, you would.
-对不起，这是.. -凯罗!
- I'm sorry. Leslie, this is-- - Carol!
凯罗.西弗，这是莱斯莉
Carol Seaver. Carol, this is Leslie Berenson.
凯罗是我亲戚，我把她当作妹妹
Carol's an old family friend, she's like the little sister I never had.
太好了
That's sweet.
-凯罗，念几年级了？ -初三
- What grade are you in, in school, Carol? - Ninth.
失陪了，我去洗手间
If you'll excuse me, I have to go to the bathroom.
麦姬，我听到声音了 咱自然点
Maggie, I think I hear them. Let's try to act natural.
嗨，甜心
Hi, honey.
-嗨，妈妈!爸爸! -嗨!
- Hi, Mom! Hi, Dad! - Hi.
我去睡了!
Well, I'm off to bed now!
等等，戏好看吗？
Wait, honey, how was the show?
戏？戏很好看!
Show? The show was great!
-晚安 -凯罗？
- Well, good night! - Carol?
-什么事？ -杰夫呢？
- Yeah, Dad? - Wheres Jeff?
天哪!把他锁在外面了!
Oh, my goodness! I must have locked him out!
杰夫，对不起
Jeffrey, I'm so sorry.
一下子忘了你
I guess I just forgot about you!
最后50步没有冲刺，是我的错
Well, it's really my fault for not wanting to sprint that last 50 yards.
对!晚安!
Right! Well, nighty-night!
凯罗!
Carol!
请听我解释.
I think I can explain.
就这样了
Well, I guess that's it.
孩子们，帮杰夫提行李上车
Hey, kids, why don't you help Jeff get his bags in the car?
-好吧，大的给我! -给我!大的给我!
- Okay. I get the big one! - No, I want the big one!
好吧，看在你是我弟弟的份上
Okay. But only because you're my brother and I love you.
屡试不爽!
Works every time!
替我跟凯罗道别
Be sure to say goodbye to Carol for me.
昨晚真是遗憾
I really feel terrible about last night.
杰夫，我们说了很多次了
Jeff, how many times do we have to tell you?
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
凯罗有点过火了，但她坚强得很
Carol gets a little carried away, but she's resilient.
伤心过后她会马上跳回正轨
She gets hurt, she bounces right back.
-弹跳力好 -杰夫!
- That's bouncy. - Jeffrey!
幸好赶得上你离开!
I'm so glad I caught you before you left!
这是我的“另一半”理查德
I'd like you to meet Richard, my "significant other."
-理查德，幸会 -什么“另一半”？
- Pleasure to meet you, Richard. - Significant other what?
理查德刚从巴黎回来
Richies been out of town. Just flew in from Paris.
去巴黎干什么了？
Now, what we're you doing in Paris, Richie?
出差
I was on business.
做盛行？
What do you do, Richie?
他是送报的!
He's our paper boy!
送这么远!
Well, that's some route.
杰夫，再见[法语]!
Well, au revoir, Jeff!
有空来坐坐
Do come back and visit soon.
我要和理查德上楼去，好好叙旧
Richie and I will be upstairs. We have so much catching up to do!
我们就喜欢这一套
We're so this way.
太棒了!
This is incredible!
今天来收报纸.
I come here to collect for the paper...
竟然发现了浪漫
and I find romance.
爱情总是那么的突如其来
But then, they say it comes when you least expect it.
放开我!滚!
Get off of me! Get out of here!
不是那边，这边
Not that way. This way.
这是二楼
We're on the second floor.
那里有水管，发挥你的想象力，滚!
There's a ledge and a drain pipe. Use your imagination. Now, out!
好吧，我走了
All right, I'm going.
等等!你是在试验我的爱？
Wait! Is this a test of my love for you?
是的，请离!
Sure. Now please, go!
我真是个混蛋!
I am such a jerk!
嗨
Hi.
-理查德呢？ -被我扔出去了
- Wheres Richie? - I threw him out.
-扔到哪里？ -外面
- Out where? - Out there.
别着急，他爬树很了得
Don't worry, he climbs like a squirrel.
你们的关系进展真快
Well, sounds like you two have a pretty stormy relationship.
拜托，我和理查德根本没有关系!
Come off it, Dad, you know Richie and I don't have a relationship!
只是假装他是我男朋友 以此来气杰夫
I just pretended he was my boyfriend so I could get back at Jeff!
-宝贝.. -杰夫肯定认为.
- Sweetheart-- - Jeff must think I'm the biggest...
我是个大傻瓜!
doofus he's ever seen!
不，杰夫不会认为你是个傻瓜
No, Carol, Jeff does not think you're a doofus.
而是一个漂亮，聪明的女孩子.
He thinks you're a beautiful, intelligent young woman...
只可惜太年幼了
who just happens to be a little too young for him.
也许吧
Yeah, sure.
这是他亲口说的 他今早很难过
Carol, that's what he said. He feels terrible about the whole thing.
每个人都会曾经冲动
Everybody acts a little crazy sometimes, you know.
冲动不代表是混蛋
That doesn't mean you're a jerk.
-冲动是真情流露 -说得对
- it just means you follow your heart. - That's right, honey.
其实你爸爸.
In fact, your father...
他在初一生物女老师面前也出过洋相
made a major bozo of himself over his seventh-grade biology teacher.
-是吗？你做些什么了？ -我没做什么.
- Yeah? What'd you do? - I didn't do anything--
拜托!
Oh, come on!
我的做法有点尴尬.
Well, mines a little embarrassing....
我绑架了她的仓鼠.
I kidnapped her hamsters and threatened to flush them...
要挟她不能嫁给社会老师
if she married Mr. Sprinkleman, the shop teacher.
-这你没告诉我 -不是真的
- You didn't tell me that. - You didn't really do that.
真的!我往头上套个袋子.
I really did! Then I put a bag over my head...
站在她的窗外唱 呢
and I stood outside her window and sang, That's What You Get For Lovin' Me.
-是吗？ -你真像个傻瓜!
- You didn't? - You must have looked like a real doofus!
那是我最要命的一次
It happens to be one of my best numbers.
我相信在“傻瓜”这个行列.
Well, I'm sure your mother's not exactly an innocent in the...
你妈妈也逃不了
doofus-for-love department!
是吗？你做了些什么？
Yeah? What have you done?
我的傻事太多了.
Well, honey, I've done so many silly things....
-数也数不清 -就挑一件吧
- I couldn't possibly list them all. - Come on, just pick one.
对，最傻的一件
Yeah. The silliest.
好吧，让我想想
Well, okay. Let's see.
好
Okay.
我有一次写了张纸条：“你真帅”
Okay. Once I wrote a note that said:
递给一个我不认识的男孩
"I think you're cute, " to a boy I didn't even know.
这就是最傻的事？
That's the silliest thing you ever did?
你妈妈就是那么滑稽
Your mother's a pretty zany lady, Carol.
也许吧，你是说这是遗传病？
So, I guess, you're trying to tell me, this problem is genetic.
-妈妈？ -什么事？
- Mom? - Yeah, sweetheart?
杰夫真的说我漂亮.
Did Jeff really say that he thinks that I'm beautiful...
而且聪明？
and intelligent?
他真的这么说
He really said that.
你若是能下去道别.
And I think he'd appreciate it...
他会很高兴的
if you went downstairs and said goodbye to him.
-他还在？ -他说会等你
- He's still here? - He said he'd wait for you.
是吗？
Yeah?
有没有说等多久？
Did he say how long?
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
理查德远从巴黎回来.
I really appreciate you coming down to say goodbye...
很感谢你还能下来道别
what with Richie coming in from Paris and all.
这个.
Yeah, well...
我们说好了 他准许我跟别的男人说再见
Richie and I have an understanding. He let's me say goodbye to other men.
凯罗，若是我不小心伤害了你 真的对不起
Look, Carol, if I hurt you in any way, I'm really sorry.
-我只是.. -别担心，我.
- I just want-- - Don't worry about it. I mean...
我们也玩得很开心
we had some good times.
-夫复何求？ -是啊
- What more can you ask for from life? - Yeah.
希望你能改观
Well, if it makes any difference...
若我们都是14岁，我也会爱得疯狂
if we we're both 14, I'd be one lovesick puppy.
-是吗？ -是的
- Really? - Really.
若我们都23岁就好玩了
Imagine how fun it would be if we we're both 23.
我23岁时，你已经32岁
Well, maybe when I'm 23 and you're 32.
你32岁时，我41岁
Or when you're 32 and I'm 41.
我风华正茂 我才看不上你这老头
Hey, I'm not gonna be wanting to date any old geezers in the prime of my life.
-若我是个有钱的老头呢？ -那就说说看
- What if I'm a rich old geezer? - We'll talk.
凯罗，我觉得你很特别
You know, you're very special, Carol.
你很快就能碰到.
Pretty soon you're gonna bump into some lucky guy your own age...
能懂得你的同龄人
who's going to find that out.
凯罗，再见
Bye, Carol.
大笨蛋，再见
Bye, Spudbrain.
-理查德! -我.
- Richie! - Well....
我应该离开吧？
Guess I should be going, huh?
理查德，我那么没礼貌，对不起
Oh, Richie. I'm sorry I was so rude to you.
-希望你能原谅我 -没关系
- I hope you can forgive me. - That's okay.
那是我人生中最美好的时光
This was the best day of my life.
-你真好人，谢谢 -嗯
- You're sweet. Thanks for everything. - Sure.
我忍不住说句，刚才无意中听到.
You know, I couldn't help but overhear what Jeff was saying about...
什么幸运的同龄人，而我刚好14岁.
some lucky guy your own age and I just thought since I am 14--
走吧!
Go!
男人啊
Men.
预备!开始!麦克，进攻!
Ready! Set! Tito, Michael, Jermaine! Hike!
-我没人防! -你们非得要打烂东西才高兴？
- I'm open! - Hey, you guys really won't be happy...
好吧，比赛停止，对不起
- until something gets broken, will you? - All right. Time out. I'm sorry.
妈妈对!
Mother's right!
开球!开球!
Hut! Hut!
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.12